<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>Zero to Hero - reflection</title>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://zerotohero.dev/tags/reflection/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://zerotohero.dev"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2021-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://zerotohero.dev/tags/reflection/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Embracing Daily Reflection</title>
        <published>2021-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2021-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Volkan Özçelik
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://zerotohero.dev/top-of-mind/probing-questions/"/>
        <id>https://zerotohero.dev/top-of-mind/probing-questions/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://zerotohero.dev/top-of-mind/probing-questions/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;size&#x2F;w1200&#x2F;2024&#x2F;03&#x2F;Volkan_Ozcelik_By_asking_myself_probing_questions_I_delve_deepe_e8494425-f36a-4e0d-b320-64efce011b35.png&quot; alt=&quot;Embracing Daily Reflection&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When everything changes, and there’s little time for practically anything, it’s
easy to get caught up in the whirlwind of tasks and responsibilities without
reflecting on our daily experiences.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the last year or so, I’ve been actively journaling. And I find
self-reflection in my journals a powerful tool for personal growth.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By asking myself probing questions, I delve deeper into my thoughts, emotions,
and actions and, more often than not, gain valuable insights that help me later.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to explore some of these questions in this &lt;strong&gt;Top of Mind&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; with you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-the-theme-of-the-day&quot;&gt;What Is the Theme of the Day?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identifying an overarching theme for the day will help you focus on it and let
you know what to do. Setting your theme establishes a guiding principle that can
shape your mindset and activities throughout the day.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recognizing your theme helps you align your goals with your actions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-can-i-drop-today&quot;&gt;What Can I Drop Today?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe in “ &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do It Tomorrow&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; “: No, “DIT” is not being lazy. You defer
things to tomorrow to do more important things today. Knowing what &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to do
is as important ( &lt;em&gt;if not more&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; ) than knowing what to do.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evaluate your to-do list and allow yourself to drop any non-essential activities
or obligations. Free up time and energy. Create space for more meaningful and
essential tasks.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-concrete-actions-will-i-take-toward-my-goal-today&quot;&gt;What concrete actions will I take toward my goal today?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Progress towards your goals is achieved through &lt;strong&gt;consistent&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; action. Identify
specific actions today to move closer to your desired outcomes. Break down your
goals into manageable steps and commit to at least one concrete action daily.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowing what to do cultivates a sense of purpose and momentum.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-was-the-highly-visible-artifact-of-my-work&quot;&gt;What was the highly-visible artifact of my work?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acknowledging the visible artifacts of your efforts reinforces a sense of
accomplishment and motivates you to continue making meaningful contributions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Realizing the impact you’ve made motivates you further. Also, when you create a
log of your achievements, it will be helpful when you want to look back in time
and admire your list of accomplishments.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-was-the-highly-visible-relationship-trail&quot;&gt;What was the highly-visible relationship trail?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our connections and relationships are vital in our personal and professional
lives. Who you know can be much more important than what you know, especially
when your impact grows in the organization.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, consider your interactions throughout the day and reflect on your impact on
others. Did you provide support, guidance, or inspiration?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assessing your relationship trail helps you nurture meaningful connections and
fosters a positive social environment.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-three-things-i-am-grateful-for-today&quot;&gt;What are three things I am grateful for today?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These gratitude exercises are a bit corny; however, research after research
demonstrates how important it is to express your gratitude and blessing in your
lives.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I decided to bite the bullet and answer this question as part of my daily
routine, and &lt;strong&gt;it helps&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can take a moment to identify three things you are grateful for each day.
They can be small moments of joy, supportive relationships, personal
achievements, or simply the beauty of nature. Practicing gratitude fosters
contentment and encourages a perspective of abundance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-made-me-feel-happy-proud-or-fulfilled-yesterday&quot;&gt;What made me feel happy, proud, or fulfilled yesterday?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This question is also related to the above gratitude question. Again, reflecting
on your positive emotions from the previous day reinforces a sense of
fulfillment and self-worth.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider the moments that brought you joy, pride, or a deep sense of
fulfillment. By acknowledging these experiences, you can identify patterns or
activities that contribute to your overall well-being and incorporate more of
them into your life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-did-i-take-care-of-my-physical-and-emotional-well-being-yesterday&quot;&gt;How did I take care of my physical and emotional well-being yesterday?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a software developer means I spend most of my day sitting comfortably on a
chair, with little to no physical activity. Yet, caring for your physical and
emotional well-being is crucial for a balanced and healthy life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this question forces me to asses what I did for my physical and mental health
and then forces me to go out grudgingly, walk for a couple of hours, breathe
fresh air, and enjoy nature without any reservations or commitments.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As its name implies, self-care can only be done by your &lt;strong&gt;self&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Recognize
your need, and take action toward it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-my-goals-or-intentions-for-tomorrow&quot;&gt;What are my goals or intentions for tomorrow?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking ahead, set clear goals or intentions for the following day. Consider
what you want to accomplish, how you want to feel, and the actions you need to
take to align with your aspirations.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By visualizing my goals and intentions, I orient myself toward them. That helps
increase the likelihood of achieving them or moving in the right direction.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-can-i-better-manage-my-time-energy-and-resources-tomorrow&quot;&gt;How can I better manage my time, energy, and resources tomorrow?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on how effectively you managed your time, energy, and resources the
previous day is helpful. This reflection enables me to refine and redefine my
approach and correct course when needed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-was-the-most-memorable-or-impactful-moment-of-yesterday&quot;&gt;What was the most memorable or impactful moment of yesterday?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human memory is not that tangible. So the earlier I reflect upon something that
has happened, the better. Chances are that I will not remember what was the
memorable thing a week ago. But since yesterday is so close, I try to capture my
impact before it fades away from my memory.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This monologue about what you have achieved and the impact you’ve made can be a
heartwarming conversation. Maybe a challenging situation taught you a valuable
lesson, or you have done an unexpected act of kindness. Reflecting on these
depends on your appreciation of those experiences. And that allows you to carry
your learnings forward.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorporating probing questions into your daily journaling practice can lead to
profound personal growth. But it doesn’t have to be a journal per se; if you are
not a writer type, you can sit down, eliminate all distractions and just “think”
about these questions. I’m sure any form of self-reflection will bring you
self-discovery and fulfillment.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that way, today’s “ &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;top of mind&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; .“&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until next time… May the source be with you 🦄.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;section-contents&quot;&gt;Section Contents&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;top-of-mind&#x2F;catch-22&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Catch 22&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;top-of-mind&#x2F;consume-less&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Consume Less&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;top-of-mind&#x2F;craft-captivating-documentation&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Craft Captivating Documentation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;top-of-mind&#x2F;keep-your-secrets&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Keep Your Secrets… Secret&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;top-of-mind&#x2F;later-does-not-exist&#x2F;&quot;&gt;‘Later’ Does Not Exist&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;top-of-mind&#x2F;perception-pivot&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Transform Feedback into Professional Mastery&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;▶ Embracing Daily Reflection&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;top-of-mind&#x2F;psst-you-dont-have-to-use-medium&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Psst… You Don’t Have to Use Medium&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;top-of-mind&#x2F;reshape-your-workspace&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Reshape Your Workspace, Reshape Your Future&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;top-of-mind&#x2F;secrets&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Secrets&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;top-of-mind&#x2F;the-dream-job&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Build Strong Connections to Land Your Dream Job&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;top-of-mind&#x2F;trust&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Trust Cultivates a Cohesive Team&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;top-of-mind&#x2F;vmware-secrets-manager&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Long Live Aegis!&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;top-of-mind&#x2F;write-to-forget&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Write to Forget&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;top-of-mind&#x2F;closure&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Closure&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;top-of-mind&#x2F;new-z2h-design&#x2F;&quot;&gt;The New Zero to Hero Design&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
