<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>Zero to Hero - hackers</title>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://zerotohero.dev/tags/hackers/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://zerotohero.dev"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2021-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://zerotohero.dev/tags/hackers/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Who Else is Ready to Hack?</title>
        <published>2021-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2021-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Volkan Özçelik
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://zerotohero.dev/roadmap/hack-the-system/"/>
        <id>https://zerotohero.dev/roadmap/hack-the-system/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://zerotohero.dev/roadmap/hack-the-system/">
&lt;div class=&quot;z2h-image&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p class=&quot;img&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&amp;#x2F;images&amp;#x2F;size&amp;#x2F;w1200&amp;#x2F;2024&amp;#x2F;03&amp;#x2F;hackers-in-action.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hack the Planet&quot;&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
    &lt;p class=&quot;alt&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center; font-style: italic;
      margin-top: -1.125em;
      font-size: 1em;&quot;&gt;Hack the Planet&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;movies-versus-reality&quot;&gt;Movies Versus Reality&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m sick of the mainstream media, movies, and everyone else depicting the term “
&lt;strong&gt;hacker&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;“ like a badass script kiddie, screwing up secret files and financial
records.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This biased representation in the media leads many people to think of the word “
&lt;strong&gt;hacker&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;“ disparagingly. Instead, the hacker is pictured as “&lt;em&gt;a fringe-type
individual with highly-specialized programming skills—who do what they do out
of greed, malice, and ill intentions&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To many people around the world, the concept of “&lt;strong&gt;hacking for good&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;” may seem
like an oxymoron. The dark image of hackers shadows the fact that people can *
&lt;em&gt;work together&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;*, in a &lt;strong&gt;collective&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; effort, to make things &lt;strong&gt;better&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; for
themselves and others around them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can proudly confess that I’m a hacker, and I am proud to be a geek, and my
friends and colleagues consider I’m damn good at it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, I have not done anything illegal so far. I sure can exploit quite a few
security holes to gather information. But why would I?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-isn-t-hacking-an-illegal-crime&quot;&gt;But… Isn’t “&lt;em&gt;Hacking&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;” an Illegal Crime?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saying “&lt;em&gt;hackers are evil because they can screw your online identity&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;” is as
equally ridiculous as saying “&lt;em&gt;car mechanics are lunatics because they can
install a time bomb in your engine&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;”.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hacking, in and of itself, is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; illegal. It is as legal as throwing a
dart. It all boils down to your &lt;strong&gt;intent&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are throwing the dart at the bull’s eye of a dartboard, then it’s fair
game; but if you are poking the dart into a person, then sorry, friend, you are
going to jail.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As in everything, &lt;strong&gt;you&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; are responsible, and &lt;strong&gt;you&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; will be kept *
&lt;em&gt;accountable&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;* for anything you do. Once this distinction is clear, then hacking
is no more dangerous than wood painting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;hacker&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; is none but an insanely &lt;strong&gt;creative&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; person. As with anything out
of the ordinary, creativity can be used for good purposes and evil purposes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;hacking-is-misunderstood&quot;&gt;Hacking Is Misunderstood&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;hacker&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; is a person who makes things work beyond perceived limits or beyond
their everyday use. Hackers enjoy &lt;strong&gt;exploring&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; the details of systems and are
&lt;strong&gt;curious&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; about how they can &lt;strong&gt;stretch&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; the system’s capabilities, unlike many
who merely prefer to learn the &lt;em&gt;minimum&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; necessary skill set to get the stuff
done.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hacking&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; is all about &lt;strong&gt;learning&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;empowerment&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;sharing knowledge&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hacking&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; a goal; it is a &lt;strong&gt;means&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to do good.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hacking is a Path&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hacking&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; is an “&lt;em&gt;attitude&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;”. There’s a &lt;strong&gt;community&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, a shared &lt;strong&gt;culture&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;,
and the accumulated &lt;strong&gt;wisdom&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; behind it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you don’t necessarily have to confine yourself to hacking software: The
“&lt;em&gt;hacker nature&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;” is independent of the particular medium the hacker works in.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter what you do, and no matter where you are if you have the hacker
spirit, you will reflect it on every action you take. And that’s something to be
proud of.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As hackers, we &lt;strong&gt;solve&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; problems; we &lt;strong&gt;build&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; things and believe in
&lt;strong&gt;collaboration&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;meritocracy&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;mutual help&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. That’s the core
essence of being a hacker.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;curiosity-kills-the-cat&quot;&gt;Curiosity Kills the Cat&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we do something really, really well, then it is &lt;strong&gt;discovering&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are &lt;strong&gt;motivated&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;curious&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;creative.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; We get so deep into how
things work that we acquire the knowledge to control them and change them to
&lt;em&gt;something else&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;; most-of-the-time something they are &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, or something that
they are not “&lt;em&gt;meant to be&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the eyes of a hacker, &lt;strong&gt;failure is not a mistake&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. It is something to be
taken a lesson from. Every failure means something new has got to be learned.
Moreover, making the same mistake twice is not that bad because, out of
&lt;strong&gt;scientific curiosity&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, that same mistake might lead to different results to
&lt;strong&gt;explore&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;teach-hacking-at-schools&quot;&gt;Teach Hacking at Schools&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A hacker’s exploratory mindset is what society needs to progress. That’s why
&lt;strong&gt;hacking must be taught in schools&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a hard day at work, I would love
to &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.eurekalert.org&#x2F;pub_releases&#x2F;2014-07&#x2F;tuhs-tur071614.php&quot;&gt;how a strand of virus can be entirely deleted from human cells for the
first time&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;,
or &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;time.com&#x2F;3013439&#x2F;language-trying-hurts-learning&#x2F;&quot;&gt;what the best way of learning a new
language is&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;,
or &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.renewableenergyworld.com&#x2F;rea&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;2014&#x2F;02&#x2F;nano-flake-technology-a-cheaper-way-to-produce-solar-cells&quot;&gt;how nanoflakes provide greater solar efficiency and may solve the energy
needs of the next generations&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This constant and ever-growing thirst for knowledge is a significant personality
trait&#x2F;disorder of a hacker:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning for the Sake of Learning&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Hackers have an irrecoverable malfunction in their brains called “&lt;strong&gt;curiosity&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to learn &lt;strong&gt;anything&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;everything&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; regardless of whether it will
be useful at work or in our daily life. It’s this “&lt;em&gt;curiosity&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;” that makes us
look at things from diagonally different angles. It’s this &lt;strong&gt;curiosity&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; that
makes a hacker figure out unconventional solutions to seemingly-hard problems in
ways that no one else can imagine.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only do we want to &lt;strong&gt;acquire&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; knowledge about everything but the kitchen
sink, but we also want to &lt;strong&gt;share&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; the culture and help others who wish to
&lt;strong&gt;walk the walk&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I bet you, if there were a way to inject this mentality to the rest of the
world, then the world would become an exponentially better place.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet still, people want to see us as skinny nerds with their $100,000 computer
set-up, using nicknames like “&lt;em&gt;M4fi4-B0i&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;” as an alias to talk to other fellow
hackers, plotting on how to take down the government.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey, wake up Trinity… Wake… Up!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, that $#!% only happens in Hollywood movies.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything the majority of the world knows about hackers is entirely and utterly
wrong. There’s a way to fix this by showing, to the rest of the world, that we,
hackers, can hack the world and make it a better place to live.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-disobedience-is-to-the-status-quo&quot;&gt;Our Disobedience Is to the Status Quo&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hacking is evolution&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever we hack, be it a programming language, a poem, a math formula, a new
color and shape for our yard fence, a new melody for a song… we create a *
&lt;em&gt;possibility&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;* of &lt;strong&gt;new&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; stuff entering our world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not always great stuff, not even stuff that works or has a particular purpose,
but &lt;strong&gt;new&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; stuff—it’s the information that matters. It’s in that information
where new possibilities for a new world emerge.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hacking is Change&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Hacking&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, is the change in the inherited characteristics of a system over
successive iterations.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This rapid iterative change gives rise to &lt;strong&gt;diversity&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;diversity&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; helps
us create &lt;strong&gt;better solutions&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hacking&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; is not a result; it is a &lt;strong&gt;movement&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; towards a future higher state:
Continuous &lt;strong&gt;improvement&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;; it is a &lt;strong&gt;curious exploration&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; that leads to
massive change.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-are-born-to-be-a-hacker&quot;&gt;You Are Born To Be a Hacker&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haven’t you ever tried to do something over and over again, in different ways,
to make it do what you wanted?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haven’t you ever disassembled a toy to see how it works while you were a child?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haven’t you ever ended your almost finished jar of Nutella with ice cream? (&lt;em&gt;if
not, try it; seriously&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That &lt;strong&gt;exactly&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; is what hacking is. You &lt;strong&gt;hack&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; stuff when you deeply examine
how things work and change it &lt;strong&gt;creatively&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; into doing what you want.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diving right into the problem and following a &lt;strong&gt;feeling&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; rather than a formal
methodology; that’s the hacker’s way of doing things.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; necessarily a bad thing. Many great inventions have spawned
out of genius minds who have not followed the conventions of what had been
believed to be accurate at their time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;every-society-needs-crazy-makers&quot;&gt;Every Society Needs Crazy Makers&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hackers are pioneers. We discover new and unusual ways of doing things; we
continuously learn, research, and explore.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hacking is about discovering and finding unusual solutions to seemingly-ordinary
problems. It’s about doing things differently with the hope of creating better
outcomes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every child is a natural hacker; ergo, &lt;strong&gt;you are born to be a hacker&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s time, society, the system, whatever you name it… makes you grind this
innate ability to a halt.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;pardon-me-so-what-is-a-hack-again&quot;&gt;Pardon Me, So What Is a “&lt;em&gt;Hack&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;” Again?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A “&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;hack&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;” is trying to do something differently.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s possible that what you create can turn out to be a solution that’s better
than similar ones that have ever been done before, or it can be some crazy shit
that no one else but you will ever use.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The essence of hacking is not the final outcome. Per contra, hacking is the road
you are &lt;strong&gt;willing&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to walk.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-makes-a-hacker&quot;&gt;What Makes a Hacker?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If everybody is born to be a hacker, then so are you. Yet, certain
characteristics make hackers stand out.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you want to walk the walk? Then just sharpen the following habits of yours:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;be-self-directed&quot;&gt;Be &lt;strong&gt;Self-Directed&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We value inner motivation and self-direction. We believe that people learn best
when they are free to explore their passions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;be-accessible&quot;&gt;Be &lt;strong&gt;Accessible&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know that no matter how much karate you know, there’s someone better than you
somewhere. So we share knowledge, share wisdom, and try to build things on top
of the shoulders of giants, and we openly share what we’ve learned on the way.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hackers are &lt;strong&gt;connected&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;thoughtful&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;supportive&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;be-curious&quot;&gt;Be &lt;strong&gt;Curious&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s the most crucial part of it. Just observe a three-year-old interacting
with the environment; how curious they are, how they question even the most
basic facts. A hacker is that three-year-old kiddo—fully grown up—without
losing their &lt;strong&gt;attention&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;intention&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;curiosity&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contrary to the popular myth, you don’t have to be a nerd to be a hacker. It
does help, however, 😉.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you read anything about coding, computers, or programming in this article
so far?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read once more, if you are not sure.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a preconceived notion that to be a hacker, you need to be good at math, or
you need to be good at cracking some code. To be a hacker, all you need to do is
be curious and be able to &lt;strong&gt;question everything&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don’t need to be a programming prodigy to achieve that. You just need to be
&lt;strong&gt;willing&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-can-hack-for-good&quot;&gt;You Can Hack For Good&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hacking, in a sense, is the ability to connect the dots to create desirable
outcomes. When this ability is used to promote ecology, sustainability, civic
life… to improve the state of the world around us, then &lt;strong&gt;beautiful things
happen&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are enough insurmountable issues that need to be tackled in the world
today. Take, for example, the climate crisis, racial injustice, all forms of
discrimination, gender inequality, war, hunger, need for clean air,
underrepresented groups, increased crime rates, torture…&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hacking is one way to create better alternatives to those. It is a way to create
a better alternative to our current way of living. Sometimes you want to flip
things around and want to convince people of actually wanting to live in a
better world sustainably and humanely. And that’s when the hackers come into
play.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s as simple as that and not simpler.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;hacking-is-not-only-for-the-elite&quot;&gt;Hacking is Not Only For the Elite&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hacking&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; is not something exclusive to a limited sub-community of geeks.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the core values of the hacker ethic is that hackers are not judged by
bogus criteria like their degrees, their education, whether they have a CS
major, or a Ph.D., or an MBA, or their race, or their position, or how long they
have been into hacking. In contrast, the &lt;strong&gt;hacker culture&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; is exceptionally
&lt;strong&gt;open&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;best idea&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;best implementation&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; always win–&lt;strong&gt;not&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; the person
who’s best at lobbying for a picture or the person who has a more prominent role
power.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which makes us &lt;strong&gt;do more&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;talk less&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;get $#!% done&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;hack-the-system&quot;&gt;Hack the System&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can learn a lot from the world, or a system, by taking it apart into pieces,
seeing how stuff works. This micro-level knowledge that you acquire helps you
create new and more exciting things.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing the system’s internals will help you understand how it is broken and what
can be done to fix it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the thing to fix it need not be a computer program:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It can be the day-long waiting lines in government agencies;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It can be &lt;em&gt;discrimination&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;racism&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; that we constantly see around;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It can be a preventing disease from killing millions;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It can be preventing child abuse;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Or it can be gender inequality…&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a matter of fact, &lt;strong&gt;something can always be better&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing is ever complete. You just have to &lt;strong&gt;go fix it&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-is-not-a-cake-walk&quot;&gt;This Is Not a Cake Walk&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be upfront, though. This is not an easy task because human beings have an
astonishing capacity to disregard all kinds of noise.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Human beings have a galactically-strong resistance to change&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it’s not just a matter of coming up with an ingenious solution, supported by
a strong argument; to make people care, you have to make your solution so *
&lt;em&gt;desirable&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;* that people cannot resist it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have to translate an &lt;strong&gt;idea&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; into something tangible that can &lt;strong&gt;blend&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
into the everyday lives of people. And this &lt;strong&gt;leap&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; can only be done with a *
&lt;em&gt;hacker’s mindset&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;*.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You do have this mindset; it’s just “&lt;em&gt;maybe&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;” you haven’t taken the red pill “
&lt;em&gt;yet&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;“.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;jfdi&quot;&gt;JFDI&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not about thinking about who we are or what hacking is.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is about “&lt;em&gt;getting your hands dirty and getting $#!% done&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;” because once
your hands are dirty, miracles can happen.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if you are unhappy with the status quo, instead of putting a black ribbon on
your social media profile, &lt;strong&gt;go and make a flocking change&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hacking is good&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;you are born to be a hacker&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Remember that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s only one question that remains…&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you ready to hack&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, may the source be with you 🦄.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;section-contents&quot;&gt;Section Contents&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;roadmap&#x2F;roadmap&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Be the Next Version of Yourself&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;▶ Who Else is Ready to Hack?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;roadmap&#x2F;chisel&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Grab Your Chisel and Start Pounding&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;roadmap&#x2F;learn-fast-remember-more&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Unlock Your Brain’s Power: Learn Fast, Remember More&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;roadmap&#x2F;the-art-of-learning&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Master Your Mind: Unleash the Power of Learning&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;roadmap&#x2F;bedtime-reading&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Resources Every Developer Must Read: No Exceptions&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;roadmap&#x2F;knowing-javascript-is-not-good-enough&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Knowing JavaScript Is Not Good Enough&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;roadmap&#x2F;learn-javascript-the-unconventional-way&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Learn JavaScript the Unconventional Way&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;roadmap&#x2F;learn-haskell&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Want to Learn JavaScript? Learn Haskell First&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;roadmap&#x2F;glossary&#x2F;&quot;&gt;A Glossary of Mostly Developer-Related Things&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;roadmap&#x2F;git&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Git Comfortable&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;roadmap&#x2F;vim&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Master Your Vim-Fu&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;roadmap&#x2F;one-does-not-simply-terminal&#x2F;&quot;&gt;One Does Not Simply Terminal 👌&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;roadmap&#x2F;design-patterns&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Paint Me Like One of Your French Design Patterns&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;roadmap&#x2F;regexp&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Tame Your Regular Expressions&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;roadmap&#x2F;security&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Security Is Not Optional&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;roadmap&#x2F;you-need-testing&#x2F;&quot;&gt;You Need Testing&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;roadmap&#x2F;a-startup-founders-bedtime-reading-list&#x2F;&quot;&gt;A Startup Founder’s Bedtime Reading List&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;roadmap&#x2F;color-theory&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Orange Is the New Purple&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;roadmap&#x2F;ramp-up-in-user-experience-design&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Ramp Up in User Experience Design&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;roadmap&#x2F;typography&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Get Better at Typography&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zerotohero.dev&#x2F;roadmap&#x2F;learning-rust&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Exploring Rust as a Go Developer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
