<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>Zero to Hero - o-ran</title>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://zerotohero.dev/tags/o-ran/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://zerotohero.dev"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2024-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://zerotohero.dev/tags/o-ran/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>O-RAN R1 Interface</title>
        <published>2024-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Volkan Özçelik
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://zerotohero.dev/inbox/o-ran-r1-interface/"/>
        <id>https://zerotohero.dev/inbox/o-ran-r1-interface/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://zerotohero.dev/inbox/o-ran-r1-interface/">&lt;p&gt;Here is a brief explanation of the O-RAN R1 Interface:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O-RAN stands for Open Radio Access Network. It is an industry standard that
defines open and interoperable interfaces for 5G RANs (Radio Access Networks).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The R1 interface is one of the key interfaces defined by O-RAN. It connects the
O-RU (O-RAN Radio Unit) and the O-DU (O-RAN Distributed Unit).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main functions of the R1 interface are:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transport of user plane data between O-RU and O-DU via Ethernet fronthaul.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
This includes downlink and uplink user data.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transport of control and management plane information between O-RU and O-DU.
This includes control signaling, synchronization, and performance measurements.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configuration and control of the O-RU by the O-DU. The O-DU can configure
parameters like frequency bands, transmission power, etc.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performance monitoring of O-RU by O-DU. The O-RU regularly sends KPIs and
measurements that allow the O-DU to monitor and manage the RU.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some key properties of the R1 interface are:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It uses Ethernet as the transport mechanism.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It supports functional split option 7-2x between O-RU and O-DU.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It provides open interfaces with standard models for configuration, control,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
performance monitoring etc.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, the R1 interface enables open and interoperable connectivity between
the radio unit and distributed unit in an O-RAN architecture. It transports user
data, control signaling, and facilitates management of the RU by the DU.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
